A Guide to the Dorothy Fox Vollertsen Papers, 1968-2001
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Dorothy Fox Vollertsen Papers, 1968-2001
The Library of Virginia
43208
7.5 cubic feet (18 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Estate of Dorothy Fox Vollertsen, Williamsburg.
Biographical Information
Dorothy Elizabeth Fox was born in Chicago, Illinois on 19 February 1910. She was the daughter of Ralph Edgar Fox (1877-1917) and Orinda Cady Daniels (1875-1968). She attended the University of Chicago, where she earned a bachelor of philosphy degree in history, and then married Dr. Arthur Hastings Vollertsen (1910-1983), an Army dentist, on 14 February 1949. They later settled in Williamsburg, Virginia. She was active in numerous hereditary and patriotic organizations, including the Daughters of the American Revolution, Daughters of Colonial Wars, Women Descendants of the Ancient and Honorable Artillery Company, General Society of Mayflower Descendants, Colonial Dames XVII Century, and the United Daughters of the Confederacy. She and her husband were the authors and editors of numerous works on Warwick County, Virginia colonial history. Dorothy Fox Vollertsen died on 15 March 2007. She and her husband are buried in Arlington National Cemetery.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1968-2001, of Dorothy Fox Vollertsen (1910-2007) of Williamsburg, Virignia, containing genealogical research for her admission, and that of her husband, Dr. Arthur H. Vollertsen (1910-1983), to various hereditary and patriotic organizations. The collection also includes materials documenting her involvement with the groups, lineage research assistance she provided to other individuals seeking admission, and numerous records submitted to the genealogical records committee of the Virginia Daughters of the American Revolution. There is also research compiled by the Vollertsens' on subjects relating to 17th and 18th century Warwick County, Virginia history, including the families of Miles Cary (1623-1667) and Capt. William Peirce (d. ca. 1647).
Contents List
- Adams. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Allerton-Newton-Wyatt. (Box 1, Folder 2-4)
- Armorial Ancestry. (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
- Atwood, Mary (Morey?). (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Barker-Tuttle. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Barr, Dixon. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Beane, Gloria Sheppard. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Bicentennial. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Bolton. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Bradford, William (Pennsylvania). (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Brewster, William (Virginia). (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Brown, Lucy Randolph Lee. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Cary Family Talk - Correspondence. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Cary Talk - Research, Working Papers, Master Copy. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Caskey, Shirley Kay Love. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Charts. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Children of the American Revolution. (Box 2, Folder 8-10)
- Children of the American Revolution - Periodicals and Flyers. (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
- Clark, Florence Curtis. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Cliffe. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Colonial Dames XVII Century. (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
- Colonial Dames XVII Century - Colonial Research and Records Committee. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Colonial Dames XVII Century - Markers. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Colonial Dames XVII - Registrar General. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Colonial Dames XVII Century - Rev. James Blair Chapter. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Colonial Daughters of the Seventeenth Century. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Connecticut Society of Genealogists. (Box 3, Folder 6-9)
- Connecticut Society of Genealogists - Membership Rosters. (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Copying Source Records (How-To). (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Couden, Dr. Henry Noble. (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Daughters of American Colonists - Regent Press File. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Daughters of Colonial Wars. (Box 4, Folder 2-4)
- Daughters of Colonial Wars - Directories, Handbooks, Programs. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Daughters of Colonial Wars - "Project Discovery". (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Daughters of the American Revolution. (Box 4, Folder 7-9)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Billmeyer Family Records. (Box 4, Folder 10)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Bland/Mouring Family Register. (Box 4, Folder 11)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Campbell Family Bible Records (Bertie County, NC). (Box 4, Folder 12)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Chilton-Elliott Family Bible Records. (Box 4, Folder 13)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Corbin Family. (Box 4, Folder 14)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Daniels, Alfred - High School Notebook, Waterbury, CT. (Box 4, Folder 15)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Danville, Virginia Marriage Records. (Box 4, Folder 16)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Eltonhead Family. (Box 4, Folder 17)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Glass, Ann Cleghorn - Supplemental Applications. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Griffin, Fauntleroy, Gwynn, Tayloe, and Corbin Families. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Hastings Family Bible Records. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Higginson Family. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Jones Family Bible Records. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Karr-Neel-Harman Families. (Box 5, Folder 6)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Keller Family. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- DAR Genealogical Records - St. Mary's Whitechapel Parish. (Box 5, Folder 8)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Soldiers of the Revolution and War of 1812 Buried in Monroe County, New York. (Box 5, Folder 9)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Waskey Family Bible Records. (Box 5, Folder 10)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Weirman Family Bible Records. (Box 5, Folder 11)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Will of Sarah Myers (Rockland County, NY). (Box 5, Folder 12)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Will of Mary Powell/Estate of Thomas Powell (Westchester County, NY). (Box 5, Folder 13)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Will of William Wilson, Bath County, 1795. (Box 5, Folder 14)
- DAR Genealogical Records - Woodley of Isle of Wight County. (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - Genealogical Talks. (Box 5, Folder 16-19)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - Library Talks. (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - Lineage Research. (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - Lineage Research Committee. (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - Membership - Proceedings and Transfers. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - National Vice Chairmen's Association. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - News Clippings. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - Pending Reports. (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - Press Book. (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - State Conferences. (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Daughters of the American Revolution - Williamsburg Chapter. (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
- Daughters of Founders and Patriots of America. (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Death Notices of Revolutionary War Soldiers. (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Delano. (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Doty (Connecticut). (Box 6, Folder 15)
- English Duplicates of Lost Virginia Records by Louis des Cognets, Jr. (Warwick County). (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Evanow, Emily Jane Stacey. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Farwell. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Federation of Genealogical Societies. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Filler. (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
- Filler, Jenna Marie and John Michael Jr.. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Floyd, Norma Jean. (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Forsyth. (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Fort Eustis Historical and Archaelogical Association. (Box 7, Folder 10-14)
- Fort Eustis Historical and Archaelogical Association - Research Reports. (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
- Foster. (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Freeman Family of North Carolina. (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Gavel Society. (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Genealogical and Historical Reference Books. (Box 8, Folder 7-9)
- "Genealogical Data of the Ancient and Honorable Artillery Company of Massachusetts, 1638-1774" by Maude Roberts Cowan. (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Genealogical Records Collected by Virginia Chapters. (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Genealogical Records Committe Reports. (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Genealogical Research Guides. (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Genealogical Seminar, 1990. (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Genealogical Seminar, 20 July 1996. (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Genealogy. (Box 9, Folder 1-9)
- Genealogy Workshop, 19 August 1996. (Box 9, Folder 10)
- General Society of Mayflower Descendants. (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Goode, Philip Hayes. (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Graves, Rebeccca - Genealogical Records. (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Gray, Anne Coles. (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Greene, Mary Ware. (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Hartel, Dorothy Wilson. (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Harwar (Allerton, Travers). (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Hereditary Register. (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Hopkins, June L.. (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Hopkins of Maryland. (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Huguenot Society. (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Jamestowne Society. (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Jones-Harwood. (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Jones, Louise Stringfield. (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Kentucky Research. (Box 10, Folder 13)
- "Lemley Lines" by Kenneth McRae Lemley. (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Lemley, Sarah. (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Lineage Book VIII. (Box 10, Folder 16-17)
- Lineage Research State Chairmen, 1983-1984. (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Lipes, Estella Suzanne Hensley. (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Longstreet, Bea Smith. (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Maglieri, Carol. (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Maryland Marriages, 1777-1800. (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Matson, Mary Florence Athearn. (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Mayer, Patricia Hatfield. (Box 11, Folder 4)
- McClure-McCorkle Families. (Box 11, Folder 5)
- McWright, Carolyn Marie Martin. (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Melyn. (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Monahan. (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Mook, Genevieve. (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Mormon Request Forms. (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Mulberry Island (Excluding Peirce). (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Munsell, Olive Estelle. (Box 11, Folder 12)
- My Country Society (Litchfield, CT). (Box 11, Folder 13)
- National Archives. (Box 11, Folder 14)
- National Society of Sons of the American Colonists. (Box 11, Folder 15)
- National Society Women Descendants of the Ancient and Honorable Artillery Company. (Box 11, Folder 16-17)
- New England Historic Genealogical Society. (Box 12, Folder 1)
- New England Historic Genealogical Society - Genealogy Catalogue (A-Z). (Box 12, Folder 2-7)
- North Carolina Genealogical Society. (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Order of Descendants of Colonial Physicians and Chirurgiens. (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Orton, Joan Hodgkinson. (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Peirce Talk - Correspondence. (Box 12, Folder 11-12)
- Peirce Talk - Research, Working Papers, Master Copy. (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Platte, Melanie. (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Read (Texas and Kentucky). (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Redd, Martha Crane Edwards. (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Roy, Joyce Bingham. (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Sampson. (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Seimes Microfilm Center. (Box 13, Folder 6-10)
- Society of Mayflower Descendants in the State of New Jersey. (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Sons of the American Revolution. (Box 13, Folder 12-14)
- South Carolina Research. (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Southworth Family. (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Tidewater Genealogical Society. (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Tinkham, Mary Nuth Rigby. (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Tuggle, Grace Streety. (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Traver. (Box 14, Folder 6)
- "A Uniform System of Citation for Lineage Papers" by Virginia Steele Wood. (Box 14, Folder 7)
- United Daughters of the Confederacy. (Box 14, Folder 8-11)
- United States Army Transportation Center and Fort Eustis - Historian. (Box 14, Folder 12)
- The Virginia Carys by Fairfax Harrison. (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Virginia DAR News Bulletin. (Box 14, Folder 14)